# TRAVIS NELSON

SOFTWARE ARCHITECT / FULL-STACK DEVELOPER / CERTIFIED SCRUM MASTER

## PROFESSIONAL STATEMENT

17+ years experience in server and client-side development. Certified Scrum Master, Certified Google Analytics, Microsoft Certified, Certified Splunk Power User 6.x, Certified Umbraco Developer Level I and II, Stanford University Software Security Foundations certificate, FraXses certification, contribution to several patent filings and awards, experience from proposal through project delivery, maintenance, and marketing.

Areas of expertise: Architecture, SOLID Web and API development, .NET, C#, SQL, Web API, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Azure, Umbraco, Git, Agile.

### SOCIAL

stackoverflow.com/u/638087

twitter.com/trnelson

in linkedin.com/in/travisneilnelson

github.com/trnelson

## CONTACT

#### **Address**

280 Jeanette St. Canton, GA 30114

#### **Email**

me@travis.io

#### Mobile/SMS

941-276-0763

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2018 - Present AgileThought

Senior Consultant

Architecture and development of "big four" enterprise microservices using C#.NET, SQL Server, Web API, Unity (IoC), Azure DevOps, React, and NHibernate. Complete ownership and responsibility for on-time delivery and demo of various platform features in a high performing, senior-level only Agile team.

2016 - 2018 **Magenic** 

Senior Consultant

Development of "big four" enterprise web software using C# .NET, SQL Server, Web API, Entity Framework, Unity (IoC), Git, Azure, Splunk. Responsible for development, architecture, proof-of-concept, and project management (Agile). Also used: Azure DevOps, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, barcode and OCR SDKs, Postman, Fiddler, Apache JMeter.

2009 - 2016 Scientific Games (formerly Williams Interactive, WMS Gaming)

Principal Software Engineer II

Full-stack development, C#.NET, CQRS, SQL Server, Web API, Autofac, JavaScript, jQuery, Agile. Site and server administration in Microsoft Azure. SCM migration and administration (GitHub Enterprise, Visual SVN), patents, process improvements within the organization. Also used: ASP.NET, WCF, Umbraco, HTML, CSS, graphic design.

2007-2009 Marketing Max

Creative Director and Lead Developer

Design and development for clients including Terminix, TruGreen, Sage Software, and ComputerJobs.com. Managed projects from consultation through design, launch, maintenance, and marketing. Development in ASP.NET using C# and SQL Server, and integration with third-party APIs and tools including Google Maps, Authorize.Net, and PayPal.

#### OTHER CONSULTING EXPERIENCE

Global Healthcare Technology and Staffing Company (Web/API Development)

- .NET, C#, Web API, .NET MVC, PostgreSQL, OAuth 2.0, Node.js, Express.js, CouchDB 115+ Year Old Industry Leader, Stone Materials (Development, Analytics, Strategy)
- Umbraco, .NET, feature development, strategy, and analytics

Healthcare Technology Startup (Web/API Development)

· Web API, .NET MVC, PostgreSQL, Angular, HTML, CSS

Global Software Training Institute (Instructor)

• Front-End Web Development, part-time instructor

Legal Technology Startup (Web Development, UI/UX, Strategy)

- Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Angular, Ruby, HTML, CSS
- Global Leader, Video Games and Digital Entertainment (Marketing/Design)
- · Adobe Photoshop, HTML, CSS, Adobe InDesign, Adobe Illustrator

# TRAVIS NELSON

SOFTWARE ARCHITECT / FULL-STACK DEVELOPER / CERTIFIED SCRUM MASTER

## PERSONAL INTERESTS

Software Architecture

Security
Design
Branding
Writing
Marketing
Business
Data/Analytics
Blockchain
Cryptography

Cryptocurrencies Instruction

Mentorship

Hand Lettering/Calligraphy

Hiking/Outdoors Fitness/CrossFit Bowling

## CONTACT

#### **Address**

280 Jeanette St. Canton, GA 30114

#### **Email**

me@travis.io

Mobile/SMS

941-276-0763

#### **EDUCATION**

2009-2011 Computer Science

Kennesaw State University, Kennesaw, GA

4.0 GPA, completed 36 credits. Courses include: Statistics, Algebra, Calculus, Macroeconomics, Microeconomics, English Composition II – Technical Writing, Psychology, Ethics, Speech Communications - Public Speaking.

1999 - 2002 Advanced Diploma - Multimedia Production

Confederation College of Applied Arts and Technology, Thunder Bay, ON

3.74 GPA, Dean's List graduate of the three-year Multimedia Production program at Confederation College, including successful completion of a four month, 576-hour internship.

### ADDITIONAL AREAS OF STUDY

SOLID design, scalable architecture, containerized apps, Docker, Kubernetes, Event Sourcing, CQRS, security, cryptography, blockchain, decentralized technologies, design patterns, test-driven development and mocking, continuous integration, Agile and Kanban, cloud services (Microsoft Azure, Amazon AWS, Rackspace Cloud), software architecture paradigms (services-oriented architecture, microservices, REST, domain-driven design, event-driven architecture, caching, table/blob/queue, web sockets), mobile, single page applications (Angular, React), UI design (Bootstrap, LESS, SASS), marketing, user experience, API design, best practices, alternate frameworks (Node,js, Python, PostgreSQL, Redis), data science, analytics, and telemetry.